<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Text on Mícheál Keating / Archive</title>
    <link>https://michealkeating.xyz/tags/text/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Text on Mícheál Keating / Archive</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://michealkeating.xyz/tags/text/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quarry, Ballyneety</title>
      <link>https://michealkeating.xyz/art/quarry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://michealkeating.xyz/art/quarry/</guid>
      <description>Sound + Single-Channel Video, Loop, 21mins&#xA;&amp;lsquo;Quarry, Ballyneety&amp;rsquo; is a quiet vocal + electronics performance responding to the deserted extraction site in County Limerick, and the wildlife now flourishing in its man-made habitat (sand martins, jackdaws, buzzards, hares among them). A peregrine falcon even makes two otherworldly interruptions during the recording. The piece was captured using a stereo pair of high-sensitivity mics, Zoom recorder and a DSLR camera.&#xA;The piece was exhibited as of &amp;lsquo;The Limerick Show&amp;rsquo; at Ormston House, 29th Nov 2024 to 1st Feb 2025.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TERRA: Digital Ephemera from DoneDeal</title>
      <link>https://michealkeating.xyz/art/terra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://michealkeating.xyz/art/terra/</guid>
      <description>Self-published artist book, 60 pages&#xA;TERRA is a personal exploration of the image culture of &amp;lsquo;Ireland&amp;rsquo;s largest motor and classifieds website&amp;rsquo; DoneDeal.ie. As the author becomes engrossed by found imagery of cars, farm machinery, animals and land for sale – themes of rural ireland, agriculture, landscape and regional identity transpire. Given some attention, DoneDeal emerges as an intriguing living document of rural Ireland, as depicted incidentally by its own inhabitants. The publication has been stocked in The Library Project, Dublin, as well as visiting Tsundoku Art Book Fair (Dublin), DISTRO (Cavan Arts Festival), Limerick Zine Fest, Rebel Reads (Cork) and The Ecliptic Newsstand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stare at the Landscape Until Time Becomes Liquid</title>
      <link>https://michealkeating.xyz/art/stare/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://michealkeating.xyz/art/stare/</guid>
      <description>Single channel video loop with sound (63mins), website-based text, and QR code installation&#xA;&amp;lsquo;Stare at the Landscape’ is a multimedia meditation on landscape – our relationship with it, the memory embodied in it, and the futurity potential in it. The work features a 63 minute single channel video of Limerick landscapes shot over a 15-month period, sound, and a web-based stream-of-consciousness text piece which viewers can access through their own devices using a QR code.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
