<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Landscape on Mícheál Keating / Archive</title>
    <link>https://michealkeating.xyz/tags/landscape/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Landscape on Mícheál Keating / Archive</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://michealkeating.xyz/tags/landscape/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quarry, Ballyneety</title>
      <link>https://michealkeating.xyz/art/quarry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://michealkeating.xyz/art/quarry/</guid>
      <description>Sound + Single-Channel Video, Loop, 21mins&#xA;&amp;lsquo;Quarry, Ballyneety&amp;rsquo; is a quiet vocal + electronics performance responding to the deserted extraction site in County Limerick, and the wildlife now flourishing in its man-made habitat (sand martins, jackdaws, buzzards, hares among them). A peregrine falcon even makes two otherworldly interruptions during the recording. The piece was captured using a stereo pair of high-sensitivity mics, Zoom recorder and a DSLR camera.&#xA;The piece was exhibited as of &amp;lsquo;The Limerick Show&amp;rsquo; at Ormston House, 29th Nov 2024 to 1st Feb 2025.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ireland (for desktop wallpapers, voice and signal processing)</title>
      <link>https://michealkeating.xyz/art/ireland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://michealkeating.xyz/art/ireland/</guid>
      <description>Single channel video with sound, 8.5mins&#xA;This piece playfully interrogates the idyllic picture of ‘Ireland’ that the country exports to the wider world. Though the landscape is often sold as a quaint and unspoiled haven, in reality, human over-extraction and ecological destruction dominates the landscape, and no stone is left unturned in the pursuit of capitalist gain.&#xA;‘Ireland’ leans into this uncanny deception: a slideshow of imagery pulled from a Google search of “Ireland” is overlayed with a turbulent voice and electronics sound performance – juxtaposing pixellated misrepresentations of the landscape with a volatile, harsh sonic accompaniment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grasslands</title>
      <link>https://michealkeating.xyz/art/grasslands/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://michealkeating.xyz/art/grasslands/</guid>
      <description>Sound performance with single channel video projection, 30mins&#xA;Grasslands&amp;rsquo; was a 30 minute solo improvised sound performance for the opening of STARLING arts space, Limerick. Keating performed with voice, signal processing, and field recording, incorporating foraged and AI-generated text relating Irish agricultural grasslands. A durational video projection of a sunset over County Limerick grasslands underpins the performance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TERRA: Digital Ephemera from DoneDeal</title>
      <link>https://michealkeating.xyz/art/terra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://michealkeating.xyz/art/terra/</guid>
      <description>Self-published artist book, 60 pages&#xA;TERRA is a personal exploration of the image culture of &amp;lsquo;Ireland&amp;rsquo;s largest motor and classifieds website&amp;rsquo; DoneDeal.ie. As the author becomes engrossed by found imagery of cars, farm machinery, animals and land for sale – themes of rural ireland, agriculture, landscape and regional identity transpire. Given some attention, DoneDeal emerges as an intriguing living document of rural Ireland, as depicted incidentally by its own inhabitants. The publication has been stocked in The Library Project, Dublin, as well as visiting Tsundoku Art Book Fair (Dublin), DISTRO (Cavan Arts Festival), Limerick Zine Fest, Rebel Reads (Cork) and The Ecliptic Newsstand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stare at the Landscape Until Time Becomes Liquid</title>
      <link>https://michealkeating.xyz/art/stare/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://michealkeating.xyz/art/stare/</guid>
      <description>Single channel video loop with sound (63mins), website-based text, and QR code installation&#xA;&amp;lsquo;Stare at the Landscape’ is a multimedia meditation on landscape – our relationship with it, the memory embodied in it, and the futurity potential in it. The work features a 63 minute single channel video of Limerick landscapes shot over a 15-month period, sound, and a web-based stream-of-consciousness text piece which viewers can access through their own devices using a QR code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MEMORY_LANE_(dump)</title>
      <link>https://michealkeating.xyz/art/memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://michealkeating.xyz/art/memory/</guid>
      <description>Single channel HD video with sound, 36.5mins&#xA;A 36 minute audiovisual thesis artwork completed for practice-based MA Art and Technology in UL. Large volumes of digital archival materials pertaining to Limerick are combined with footage of the Limerick landscape, to explore the land as a haunted, digitally mediated palimpsest. The piece probes questions of memory, place, hauntology, nostalgia, historical narratives, temporality and the digital archive.&#xA;The piece was exhibited in &amp;lsquo;The Limerick Show&amp;rsquo; (2022) in Ormston House.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FARM</title>
      <link>https://michealkeating.xyz/art/farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://michealkeating.xyz/art/farm/</guid>
      <description>Single channel HD video with sound, 9.5mins&#xA;‘FARM’ is a short video art experiment in bringing the past, present and future of an Irish farming landscape into question. It was filmed on the artist&amp;rsquo;s family&amp;rsquo;s farm in County Limerick. An early video work as part of MA Art and Technology in UL. Featured music is &amp;lsquo;Oraison&amp;rsquo; by Olivier Messiaen.&#xA;Watch here</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
